A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Richard M. Krasno FA564
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Richard M. Krasno
1975-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Krasno, Richard M.
Ford Foundation
FA564
1.8 Cubic Feet 2 boxes (1 cubic foot box, 1 document box)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Alphabetical (A-Z)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Richard M. Krasno's career in education has included positions in academia, philanthropy, and government. Krasno worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. In 1974, he joined the Foundation as a Program Advisor in the Latin America and the Caribbean, Brazil Program. He then became a Program Officer in the umbrella Latin America and the Caribbean Program before moving to the Middle East and Africa Program.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Krasno served in the United States Department of Education as Deputy Assistant to the Secretary of Education. He then had executive positions at the Institute of International Education, the Monterey Institute of International Studies, and the William R. Kenan, Jr, Charitable Trust. He later became Lead Director for Ladenburg Thalmann Financial Services.
Krasno earned a Ph.D. from Stanford University and worked as an assistant professor at the University of Chicago prior to joining the Ford Foundation.
Scope and Contents
General files of Richard M. Krasno.
- Asia, 1979 (Box 1)
- Brazil, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
- Chafkin Proposal, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Cuba, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- East Africa, 1977 (Box 1)
- ETS Evaluation Meeting -- Washington DC, 1978 December 6 (Box 1)
- Department of Education -- Transition Team, 1980 (Box 1)
- Education and Public Policy Discussion with Mr. Thomas, 1979 (Box 1)
- Education Resource Basis, 1980 (Box 1)
- Foundation for International Technical Cooperation (FITC), 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Grants, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
- Health, Education and Welfare (HEW) -- Peter Bell, 1979 (Box 1)
- Humanities -- Latin America, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
- ICBF Supplement, 1978 (Box 1)
- Iftah Ya Sim Sim, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- International Division Committee on Women's Programs, 1978 (Box 1)
- Israel-Egypt Exchange, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
- Office of Latin America and the Caribbean (OLAC) Budget -- FY 1980-81, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Office of Latin America and the Caribbean (OLAC) and the Arts, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Pollitt Study -- Comments, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
- Puryear Visit, 1978 March 27-30 (Box 1)
- Sex Differences Meeting, 1979 January 5-9 (Box 2)
- Thailand, 1979 (Box 2)
- Working Session on Adult Education, International Aid and Poverty, 1980 June 2-3 (Box 2)
- World Bank, The, 1978 (Box 2)